NAOMI ENIOLA ADESIYAN

Abbey Wood, London SE2

■ naomiadesiyan@hotmail.com | • 07456433694 | • naomieniola | in Naomi Eniola Adesiyan

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a driven Computer Science with Business graduate who excels academically and brings valuable experience from previous roles and internships. My skill set spans front-end, back-end, and web development, interaction design, and agile practices. I have a strong understanding of object-oriented programming principles, time complexities, data structures and algorithms, and the software development life cycle. Additionally, I recognise the importance of version control and consistently apply best practices for writing clean, maintainable code.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express.js, Node.js, C#, PHP, SQL, PostgreSQL
- Frameworks: Bootstrap, ASP.NET MVC, React.js
- Tools: Visual Studio 2022, VS Code, Azure Data Studio, Docker, Figma, Microsoft Office Suite, GitHub
- Methodologies: Agile

EXPERIENCE

May 2024 – Sep 2024 **Software Development and Engineering Trainee**Robert Walters – London (Remote)

- Developed over 5 applications using C# implementing the entire Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- Designed and implemented Microsoft SQL databases including creating ERDs and writing complex SQL queries for data retrieval and analysis.
- Used ASP.NET MVC framework to manage interactions between the database and the user interface.
- Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript and razor pages to design the front-end.
- Deployed applications using Docker, creating and managing containers.
- Conducted unit testing and Benchmarking, ensuring high-quality and reliable code delivery.
- Collaborated with my team of 5 developers on GitHub, using branches in Visual Studio to manage source code, implement features, and resolve conflicts efficiently.

WORK HISTORY

Sep 2023 – Dec 2023 **Team Member** Lovisa - Birmingham

- Offered outstanding customer service and gave tailored fashion suggestions.
- Performed spot checks on all tills, making sure they had enough change in them.
- Accounted for all cash at the end of each day.
- Ran reports to look at performance.
- Performed piercing services.
- Promoted add-on products, resulting in increased sales.

May 2022 - Sep 2023

Web Developer Placement

OnlineNaira - London

- Developed and implemented features using CSS, JavaScript, and PHP code, enhancing website functionality and user experience.
- Managed the OnlineNaira website with a team of 3 developers, contributing to both front-end and back-end tasks, including integration with databases and servers.
- Used a wide range of over 7 web technologies including PHP, JavaScript/jQuery, HTML, cPanel, WHM, and SQL.
- Actively participated in project management using JIRA + Slack, gaining experience with agile methodologies like Kanban.
- Communicated effectively with team members, providing regular status updates, and proactively addressing any issues or roadblocks.

EDUCATION

Sep 2020 - Jun 2024

BSc (Hons) Computer Science with Business (ITMB with placement year)

Aston University | Birmingham

• First class honours

Relevant Modules:

- Object Oriented Programming
- Mathematics for Computing Professionals
- Interaction Design
- Software Project Management
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Human-Computer Interaction
- Software Engineering

Sep 2018 - Jun 2020

A-levels

Christ the King, St. Mary's Sixth Form College | Sidcup, Bexley

- Information Technology (A*)
- Law (B)
- Business Studies (B)
- Member of the French elective

Sep 2013 - Jul 2018

GCSEs

Harris Garrard Academy | Thamesmead

• 10 GCSEs grades A-B

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft Certified: Azure AI Fundamentals
- Foundational C# with Microsoft

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Aston Achievement Scholarship - (Students holding BBB+ in A-Levels)

HOBBIES AND INTEREST

- Gym
- Reading
- Music (Guitar)
- Drawing
- Gaming
- Designing accessories, hair, and clothing for 3D models in the Sims 4 and ROBLOX using Blender, Marvelous Designer and Adobe Substance Painter

LANGUAGES	
English	French
Native	Intermediate